Guide to the Matthew Vassar Papers, 1730-1975
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
- Series I. Materials Concerning Vassar College
  - Letters of application and draft replies
    - To Cornelia E. Jewett, 17 Feb 1863 (Folder 7.196_006)
    - From Miss Cornelia E. Jewett, 13 Feb 1863 (Folder 7.196_007)
    - From Mrs. C.M. Fitch, 14 Feb 1863 (Folder 7.196_008)
    - To Mrs. C.M. Fitch, 17 Feb 1863 (Folder 7.196_009)
    - From Florence H. Condit, Feb 1863 (Folder 7.196_010)
    - To Florence H. Condit, 23 Feb 1863 (Folder 7.196_011)
    - To Ruthie E. Barber, 31 Mar 1863 (Folder 7.197_001)
    - From Ruthie E. Barber, 7 Apr 1863 (Folder 7.197_002)
    - From Fannie L. Card, 6 Apr 1863 (Folder 7.197_003)
    - From Jesse Hawley, 4 May 1863 (Folder 7.197_004)
    - From Sidney Andrews, 7 May 1863 (Folder 7.197_005)
    - From Elizabeth Geiger, 7 May 1863 (Folder 7.197_006)
    - From Christine M. Benedict, 4 Jul 1863 (Folder 7.198_001)
    - To Christine M. Benedict, 10 Jul 1863 (Folder 7.198_002)
    - To Miss Caroline E. Williams, 27 Aug 1863 (Folder 7.198_003)
    - From Mary Towne, 5 Oct 1863 (Folder 7.198_004)
    - To Mary Towne, 6 Oct 1863 (Folder 7.198_005)
    - From Martha E. Livingston, 13 Dec 1863 (Folder 7.198_006)
    - From Ellen M. Davis, 23 Jan 1864 (Folder 7.199_001)
    - To Miss Davis, 26 Jan 1864 (Folder 7.199_002)
    - From Mary C. Raymond, 25 Jan 1864 (Folder 7.199_003)
    - To Miss Raymond, 1 Feb 1864 (Folder 7.199_004)
    - From Ellen M. Davis, 1 Feb 1864 (Folder 7.199_005)
    - To Ellen M. Davis, 3 Feb 1864 (Folder 7.199_006)
    - From Mary L. Booth, 22 Feb 1864 (Folder 7.199_007)
    - From B. Richards, 23 Feb 1864 (Folder 7.199_008)
    - From Caroline E. Williams, 15 Mar 1864 (Folder 7.200_001)
    - To Caroline E. Williams, undated (Folder 7.200_002)
    - From Hiram Veltman, 19 Mar 1864 (Folder 7.200_003)
    - To Hiram Veltman, undated (Folder 7.200_004)
    - From Julius S. Clarke, 21 Mar 1864 (Folder 7.200_005)
    - To Julius [C.] Clarke, 22 Mar 1864 (Folder 7.200_006)
    - From William J. Burr, 26 Apr 1864 (Folder 7.200_007)
    - From Mary S. Towne, 8 May 1864 (Folder 7.200_008)
    - From Henry Stables [Stabler], 9 May 1864 (Folder 7.200_009)
    - From Miss M.L., 10 May 1864 (Folder 7.201_001)
    - From Gage, M.E.J., 10 May 1864 (Folder 7.201_002)
    - From Kate M. Anderson, 14 May 1864 (Folder 7.201_003)
    - From C.A. De Vere, 16 May 1864 (Folder 7.201_004)
    - From A.H. Todd, 17 May 1864 (Folder 7.201_005)
    - From Henry S. Washburn, 19 May 1864 (Folder 7.201_006)
    - From Charles S. Arthur, 20 May 1864 (Folder 7.201_007)
    - From Julia A.M. Gould, 21 May 1864 (Folder 7.201_008)
    - From A.W. Creveling, 23 May 1864 (Folder 7.201_009)
    - From Minnie Lehman, 23 May 1864 (Folder 7.201_010)
    - From Warwick P. Miller, 23 May 1864 (Folder 7.201_011)
    - From Samuel Shardlow, 26 May 1864 (Folder 7.201_012)
  - Letter Book, 1860-1868 (Folder 8.202)
  - College Grounds Admissions – Rev. F.B. Wheeler, 1866 (Folder 7.203)
  - College Grounds Admissions – Rev. F.B. Wheeler, 12 Feb 1867 (Folder 7.203)
  - College Grounds Admissions – W.J.W. Draw, undated (Folder 7.203)
  - Vassar, Matthew, "To the Trustees of Vassar Female College...", 26 Feb 1861 (Oversize Folio Box)
  - Address to Board of Trustees, 26 Feb 1861 (Folder 1.204)
  - Address to Board of Trustees, 25 Feb 1862 (Folder 1.205)
  - Address to Board of Trustees, 24 Jun 1862 (Folder 1.206)
  - Address to Board of Trustees, 30 Jun 1863 (Folder 1.207)
  - Address to Board of Trustees, 23 Feb 1864 (Folder 1.208)
  - Address to Board of Trustees, 28 Jun 1864 (Folder 1.209)
  - Address to Board of Trustees, 12-13 Apr 1865 (Folder 1.210)
  - Address to Board of Trustees, 27 Jun 1865 (Folder 1.211)
  - Address to Board of Trustees, 26 Jun 1866 (Folder 1.212)
  - Address to Board of Trustees, draft, 25 Jun 1867 (Folder 1.213)
  - Address to Board of Trustees, 25 Jun 1867 (Folder 1.214)
  - Address to Board of Trustees, draft, 23 Jun 1868 (Folder 1.215)
  - Address to Board of Trustees, draft, 23 Jun 1868 (Folder 1.216)
  - Address to Board of Trustees (with X on page 11 to mark where Vassar stopped reading), 23 Jun 1868 (Folder 1.217)
  - Address to Board of Trustees (facsimile of last page with note by B.J. Lossing on Matthew Vassar's death, 23 Jun 1868 (Folder 1.218)
  - Communications to the Board of Trustees (collected addresses), 1886 (Folder 1.219)
  - Notes for speech at 3rd [Anniversary] Union, undated (Folder 1.220)
  - Fragment of unidentified address/letter, undated (Folder 1.221)
  - Deeds, mortgages relating to Vassar Female College (folder 1 of 2), 1858-1863 (Folder 1.222)
  - Deeds, mortgages relating to Vassar Female College, (folder 2 of 2), Dec 1860 (Folder 24.222A (Oversize))
  - Vassar College Farm: Inventory of Matthew Vassar's personal property, Mar 1861 (Folder 1.223)
  - Vassar College tuition receipt, Sep 1867; (1 item) (Folder 1.901)
- Series II. Personal and Civic Life
  - Autobiographical Sketch: "There is no facility of the mind...", (1 item) (Folder 9.224)
  - Autobiographical sketches, "The subject of the following memoir..." and, "The subject of this memoir...", (2 items) (Folder 9.225)
  - Autobiographical sketch: "A brief memorandum of a few of the incidents in the life...", 1854; (1 item and transcript) (Folder 9.226)
  - Autobiography (notebook), (1 item)* (Folder 10.227)
  - Diary, v. 1, 1 Feb - 8 Oct 1862; (1 item)* (Folder 10.228)
  - Diary, v. 2, 12 Oct 1863 - 9 May 1864; (1 item)* (Folder 10.229)
  - Diary, v. 3, 9 May - 12 Oct 1864; (1 item)* (Folder 10.230)
  - Diary, v. 4, 26 Sep 1864 - 30 Jun 1865; (1 item)* (Folder 10.231)
  - Diary, v. 5, 9 Nov 1865 -13 Apr 1866; (1 item)* (Folder 10.232)
  - Diary, v. 6, 14 Apr - 13 Sep 1866; (1 item)* (Folder 10.233)
  - Diary, v. 7, 4 Feb - 22 Jun 1867; (1 item)* (Folder 10.234)
  - Diary, v. 8, 22 Jun 1867 - 26 Jan 1868; (1 item)* (Folder 10.235)
  - Diary, v. 9, 28 Nov 1867 - 13 Apr 1868; (1 item)* (Folder 10.236)
  - Diary, v. 10, 14 Apr - 23 Jun 1868; (1 item)* (Folder 10.237)
  - From George Swain, 1815; (1 letter) (Folder 7.238)
  - From Jeremiah Dodge, 12 Aug 1816; (1 letter)** (Folder 9.239)
  - From John Harbottle, 6 Feb 1833; (1 letter)** (Folder 9.240)
  - To Gail Tallmadge, 30 Apr 1835; (1 letter) (Folder 7.241)
  - From John Harlbottle, 2 Apr 1837; (1 letter and transcript) (Folder 7.242)
  - To Oliver [Booth?], 27 Jun 1837; (1 letter)** (Folder 7.243)
  - To My Dear Friend, 24 Nov 1837; (1 letter)** (Folder 7.244)
  - From Sophia Harlbottle, 15 Oct 1839; (1 letter and transcript) (Folder 7.245)
  - From Robert A. Forsyth, 17 Jun 1842; (1 letter) (Folder 7.246)
  - From Thomas Sommers, 6 Mar 1843; (1 letter) (Folder 7.247)
  - From W.[S?]. Coolidge, 21 Mar 1843; (1 letter) (Folder 7.248)
  - To Dear Sirs, 8 Jun 1844; (1 letter)** (Folder 9.249)
  - From F.W. Porter Co., 5 Aug 1844; (1 letter) (Folder 11.250)
  - From F.W. Porter, 27 Aug 1844; (1 letter) (Folder 11.251)
  - From Kitchum [Jo?], 27 Aug 1844; (1 letter) (Folder 11.252)
  - From A.J. Prime, 9 Sep 1844; (1 letter) (Folder 11.253)
  - From Thomas D. Burrall, 8 Nov 1844; (1 letter) (Folder 11.254)
  - From James Hooker, 9 Jan 1845; (1 letter) (Folder 11.255)
  - To [Lydia Booth], 20 Aug 1845; (1 letter) (Folder 11.903)
  - To Dear Sir, 27 Jan 1846; (1 letter)** (Folder 11.256)
  - To Dear Sir, 22 Jul 1867; (1 letter)** (Folder 11.257)
  - To A.P. Booth, 27 Feb 1854; (1 letter) (Folder 11.258)
  - To Gov. Seymour (New York), 27 Mar 1854; (1 letter) (Folder 11.259)
  - To Hon. J.E. Allen, 28 Feb 1855; (1 letter) (Folder 11.260)
  - To Deacon William Colgate, 29 Mar 1856; (1 letter, seal, and transcript) (Folder 11.261)
  - To Maria Booth, 1 Dec 1856; (1 letter)** (Folder 11.262)
  - To Dr. Benjamin Fowler, [1857?]; (1 letter and envelope) (Folder 11.263)
  - To Oliver, 12 Jul 1858; (1 letter)** (Folder 11.264)
  - To A.R. Booth, 16 Apr 1860; (1 letter)** (Folder 11.265)
  - To whom it may concern, 11 Jun 1860; (1 letter) (Folder 11.266)
  - To Dear Nephew, 24 Jun 1861; (1 letter)** (Folder 11.267)
  - To Samuel Butler, 2 Jun 1863; (1 letter) (Folder 11.268)
  - From Josiah L. Young, Esq., 17 Sep 1863; (1 letter) (Folder 11.904_1)
  - To Josiah L. Young, Esq., 22 Sep 1863; (1 letter) (Folder 11.904_2)
  - From Josiah L. Young, Esq., 29 Sep 1863; (1 letter) (Folder 11.904_3)
  - To Charles Vassar, 16 Nov 1866; (1 letter) (Box 41)
  - To VanValkenburgh and Brown, 23 Jan 1867; (1 letter) (Folder 11.269)
  - To John Clay, 8 Mar 1867; (1 note) (Folder 23.712)
  - To C.G.S. Tooker, 20 Aug 1867; (1 letter) (Folder 11.270)
  - To I.W. Dean, 20 Aug 1867; (1 letter) (Folder 11.271)
  - To Robert E. Gray, 6 Jan 1868; (1 letter, inscription, and transcript) (Folder 11.272)
  - To Richard P. Morgan, 3 Feb 1868; (1 letter and envelope) (Folder 11.273)
  - From Baptist Church, Poughkeepsie, 21 Feb 1868; (1 framed letter) (Framed Storage 1.7)
  - To [Maria Louise Booth], 28 May 1868; (1 letter)** (Folder 11.274)
  - To F.W. Davis, 11 Jun 1868; (1 letter) (Folder 11.275)
  - To George H. Carlies, undated; (1 letter) (Folder 11.276)
  - To Mrs. Bishop, undated; (1 letter) (Folder 11.277)
  - To James Vassar, 4 Apr [no year]; (1 letter)** (Folder 11.278)
  - Communications concerning Baptist Church, 1842; (3 items) (Folder 9.279)
  - Communications concerning Baptist Church, 1843; (4 items) (Folder 9.280)
  - Communications concerning Baptist Church, Jul 1844; (13 items) (Folder 9.281)
  - Communications concerning Baptist Church, Aug - Sep 1844; (7 items) (Folder 9.282)
  - Communications concerning Baptist Church, Dec 1844; (4 items) (Folder 9.283)
  - Defense in response to meeting of 9 Dec 1844, (1 item) (Folder 9.284)
  - Communications concerning Baptist Church, 1845; (3 items) (Folder 9.285)
  - Affidavits concerning VanLoon/Baptist Church, Mar 1845; (10 items) (Folder 9.286)
  - Correspondence with General James Tallmadge, concerning Baptist Church, Feb 1845, Feb 1846; (4 letters and draft) (Folder 9.287)
  - Letters to newspapers (mss), 1844 - 1845; (7 items) (Folder 9.288)
  - Advocate; clippings concerning Baptist Church, Jul - [Sep?] 1845; (2 items) (Folder 9.289)
  - Poughkeepsie Journal and Eagle; clippings concerning Baptist Church, Feb - May 1845; (11 items) (Folder 9.290)
  - The Safeguard; clippings and issues concerning Baptist Church, Dec 1844 - Feb 1845; (8 items) (Folder 25.291 (Oversize))
  - Memoranda; concerning Baptist Church Affairs, 1844 - [1845?]; (3 items) (Folder 9.292)
  - Baptist Church: Pews, burial grounds, and other financial papers, undated; (5 items) (Folder 9.293)
  - Baptist Church burying grounds and pews, undated; (2 items) (Folder 25.293A (Oversize))
  - Baptist Church: Bonds, deeds, and mortgages, 1830-1840; (3 items) (Folder 9.294)
  - Baptist Church: Bonds, deeds, and mortgages, 1830-1840; (4 items) (Folder 24.294A (Oversize))
  - Baptist Church: Bonds, deeds, and mortgages, 1841-1845; (3 items) (Folder 9.295)
  - Baptist Church: Bonds, deeds, and mortgages, 1841-1845; (3 items) (Folder 24.295A (Oversize))
  - Baptist Church handbills, Jan 1845; (2 items) (Folder 9.296)
  - Financial Papers - Poughkeepsie Board of Trustees, undated; (9 items) (Folder 9.297)
  - Papers concerning new street between Main and Mansion Streets, petitions, etc. for, undated; (4 items) (Folder 9.298)
  - Papers concerning new street between Main and Mansion Streets, petitions against, undated; (3 items) (Folder 9.299)
  - Papers concerning new street between Main and Mansion Streets, survey map, undated; (1 item) (Folder 25.300 (Oversize))
  - Autographs, calling cards, invitation, miscellaneous, 1868, undated; (13 items) (Folder 12.301)
  - Autographs, undated; (2 envelopes) (Folder 12.301A)
  - Personal Writings - "WoodDuck" (poem), "Life of Poor Tip", undated; (3 items) (Folder 12.302)
  - Address to Poughkeepsie Lyceum (typescript), undated; (1 item) (Folder 12.303)
  - Papers: Concerning Death Penalty (author unknown), undated; (2 items) (Folder 12.304)
  - Miscellaneous contemporary printed material, undated; (2 items) (Folder 12.305)
  - Gift of books/journals from Matthew Vassar, undated; (1 item) (Folder 12.306)
  - Baptist Society Memberships of Matthew and Catherine Vassar, undated; (4 items) (Folder 12.307)
  - Baptist Society Memberships of Matthew and Catherine Vassar, undated; (4 items and 3 photocopies) (Folder 24.307A (Oversize))
  - Fire Co. appointment, 1823; (1 item) (Folder 12.308)
  - Passport, undated; (1 item) (Folder 12.309)
  - Lithographs: "First Residence of Matthew Vassar at Poughkeepsie" and "Birthplace of Matthew Vassar, E. Durham, Norfolk, England,", undated; (1 framed item) (Box 50)
  - Lithographs: Portrait of Matthew Vassar, engraving by H. Wright Smith, undated; (2 framed items) (Box 50)
  - Painting: Pringle, James, "Northumberland," painting of the ship Matthew Vassar travelled on to England, 1845; (1 framed item) (Framed Storage 1.2)
  - Acorn Grave Monument: photos, sketches, including sketch by Matthew Vassar, undated; (7 items) (Folder 13.310)
  - Grave site; deeds, contract for curbing, undated; (11 items) (Folder 13.311)
  - Springside; map, index to architectural plans, undated; (2 items) (Folder 13.312)
  - Springside: map, undated; (1 reproduction) (Folder 25.312A (Oversize))
  - Springside: "Specifications for building the residence of M. Vassar Esq" (apparently never built), undated; (1 item) (Folder 13.313)
  - Springside: Photocopy of "Specifications for building the residence of M. Vassar Esq", undated; (1 item) (Folder 13.314)
  - Springside: contract with C.N. Bement, 1 Apr 1859 - 1 Apr 1860; (1 item) (Folder 13.315)
  - Springside: Admission to estate (photocopy - original in folder 203), (1 item) (Folder 13.316)
  - Springside: Condominium development, (5 items) (Folder 13.317)
  - Springside: contemporary printed references, (11 items) (Folder 13.318)
  - Springside: "Prophet with honor: The career of Andrew Jackson Downing 1815-1852", (1 item) (Folder 13.319)
  - Springside: "J. Downing's only extant garden" by Robert M. Toole, (1 item) (Folder 13.320)
  - Springside: newspaper clippings, 1943-1973; (32 items) (Folder 13.321)
  - Springside: newspaper clippings, 1975-; (10 items) (Folder 13.322)
  - Springside: printed references, undated; (9 items) (Folder 13.323)
  - Springside: Photograph, "Founder's Spring Side Cottage," photographed by S.L. Walker, 1859; (1 framed item) (Framed Storage 1.1)
  - Springside: Photograph, "Founder's Spring Side Cottage," [photographed by S.L. Walker?], [1859?]; (1 framed item) (Framed Storage 1.1)
  - Springside: photographs, drawings as published, undated; (25 items) (Folder 13.324)
  - Springside: "Springside Mazurka" by Charles Grube, (1 original, 2 copies) (Folder 13.329)
  - Calvert Vaux proposed plans: Pencil sketch of exterior, circa 1850; (8.25 x 10.125 in) (Folder 45.1 (Oversize))
  - Calvert Vaux proposed plans: Plan of chamber floor, circa 1850; (15.25 x 12.25 in) (Folder 45.2 (Oversize))
  - Calvert Vaux proposed plans: Plan of principal floor, circa 1850; (15.25 x 12.25 in) (Folder 45.3 (Oversize))
  - Calvert Vaux proposed plans: Design for a villa, southwest view, circa 1850; (12.25 x 9.25 in) (Folder 45.4 (Oversize))
  - Calvert Vaux proposed plans: Sketch for a gate lodge, circa 1850; (7.25 x 5 in) (Folder 45.5 (Oversize))
  - Downing – Design for a gardener's cottage: No. 2 Basement plan, circa 1850; (14.5 x 10 in) (Folder 45.6 (Oversize))
  - Downing – Design for a gardener's cottage: No. 3 Attic plan, circa 1850; (14.5 x 9.75 in) (Folder 45.7 (Oversize))
  - Downing – Design for a gardener's cottage: No. 4 Front Elevation, circa 1850; (14.5 x 10 in) (Folder 45.8 (Oversize))
  - Downing – Design for a gardener's cottage: No. 5 Back Elevation, circa 1850; (14.5 x 10 in) (Folder 45.9 (Oversize))
  - Downing – Design for a gardener's cottage: No. 6 Side Elevations, circa 1850; (14.5 x 10 in) (Folder 45.10 (Oversize))
  - Downing – Design for barns, stable: Sketch for barn, stables, etc – front elevation, circa 1850; (16.25 x 6.5 in) (Folder 45.11 (Oversize))
  - Downing – Design for barns, stable: Sketch for barn, stables, etc – front elevation, circa 1850; (16.25 x 6.5 in) (Folder 45.11 (Oversize))
  - Downing – Design for barns, stable: No. 1 Ground plan, circa 1850; (29.125 x 21.25 in) (Map Case Drawer 7 - Folder 47.12 (Oversize))
  - Downing – Design for barns, stable: No. 2 Back elevation and ground floor, circa 1850; (29.125 x 21.25 in) (Map Case Drawer 7 - Folder 47.13 (Oversize))
  - Downing – Design for a lodge: No. 3 Front elevation, circa 1850; (30 x 21.75 in) (Map Case Drawer 7 - Folder 47.14 (Oversize))
  - Downing – Design for a lodge: Plan of principal floor, circa 1850; (27.75 x 21.75 in) (Map Case Drawer 7 - Folder 47.15 (Oversize))
  - Downing – Design for a lodge: No. 2 Plan of basement and bedroom floor, circa 1850; (22.5 x 15.5 in) (Folder 46.16 (Oversize))
  - Downing – Design for a lodge: No. 4 North elevation, circa 1850; (21.5 x 14.5 in) (Folder 46.17 (Oversize))
  - Downing – Design for a lodge: No. 5 Side elevation, circa 1850; (21.5 x 14.75 in) (Folder 46.18 (Oversize))
  - Downing – Design for a lodge: No. 6 Section transversely, circa 1850; (21.5 x 15 in) (Folder 46.19 (Oversize))
  - Downing – Design for a Residence: No. 1 Plan of cellar and foundations, circa 1850; (29.25 x 21 in) (Map Case Drawer 7 - Folder 48.20 (Oversize))
  - Downing – Design for a Residence: No. 2 Principal floor, circa 1850; (29.5 x 21 in) (Map Case Drawer 7 - Folder 48.21 (Oversize))
  - Downing – Design for a Residence: No. 3 Chamber plan, circa 1850; (29.5 x 21 in) (Map Case Drawer 7 - Folder 48.22 (Oversize))
  - Downing – Design for a Residence: No. 5 Principal elevation, circa 1850; (29.5 x 21 in) (Map Case Drawer 7 - Folder 48.23 (Oversize))
  - Downing – Design for a Residence: No. 5 Attic plan, circa 1850; (29.5 x 21 in) (Map Case Drawer 7 - Folder 48.24 (Oversize))
  - Downing – Design for a Residence: No. 6 West elevation, circa 1850; (29.5 x 21 in) (Map Case Drawer 7 - Folder 49.25 (Oversize))
  - Downing – Design for a Residence: No. 7 North elevation, circa 1850; (29.5 x 17 in) (Map Case Drawer 7 - Folder 49.26 (Oversize))
  - Downing – Design for a Residence: No. 8 East elevation, circa 1850; (29.5 x 18.5) (Map Case Drawer 7 - Folder 49.27 (Oversize))
  - Downing – Design for a Residence: No. 9 Roof Plan, circa 1850; (28.5 x 19.25 in) (Map Case Drawer 7 - Folder 49.28 (Oversize))
  - W.D. Jones engraving: Map of Springside, in color, undated; (38 x 26 in) (Map Case Drawer 7 - Folder 49.29 (Oversize))
- Series III. Matthew Vassar and Company, Brewers
  - Agreements concerning Brewery, 1829, 1839, 1862; (3 items) (Folder 13.325)
  - Matthew Vassar Co. Partnership Agreements (folder 1 of 2), 1829-1836; (4 items) (Folder 13.326)
  - Matthew Vassar Co. Partnership Agreements (folder 2 of 2), 1830-1860; (2 items) (Folder 13.327)
  - Purser/Vassar Partnership: Agreements, mortgage, etc., undated; (6 items) (Folder 13.328)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Vassar to F. Thompson, 22 Jun 1815; (1 letter) (Folder 14.330)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: George Morell to Dear Sir, [6?] Dec 1815; (1 letter)** (Folder 14.331)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Jarvis, Richard to Vassar, 26 Feb 1816; (1 letter)** (Folder 12.332)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Vassar to Tucker, Henry, 15 Apr 1816; (1 letter) (Folder 12.333)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Dodge, Dr. to Mess.Vassar, Conklin, 22 May 1816; (1 letter)** (Folder 14.334)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: [Kerr?], Thomas to James Vassar, 24 May 1816; (1 letter)** (Folder 12.335)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Hughes, Henry, Jr. to Vassar Co., 16 Jul 1816; (1 letter)** (Folder 12.336)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Wilmeraing, Morgan to Mr. Conklin, 17 Sep 1816; (1 letter)** (Folder 12.337)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Wilmeraing, Morgan to Vassar Co., 24 Sep 1816; (1 letter)** (Folder 12.338)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Purser, Thomas to James Vassar, 7 Nov 1816; (1 letter)** (Folder 12.339)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Stokes, [?]udway to Vassar Co., 11 Dec 1816; (1 letter)** (Folder 12.340)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Stokes, [?]udway to Vassar Co., 1 Feb 1817; (1 letter)** (Folder 14.341)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Dodge, Daniel to Vassar Co., 27 Mar 1817; (1 letter)** (Folder 12.342)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Dodge, Daniel to Vassar Co., 27 Mar 1817; (1 letter)** (Folder 12.343)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Wilson, Thomson to Vassar Co., 19 Apr 1817; (1 letter)** (Folder 12.344)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Wilson, Thomson to Vassar Co., 29 Apr 1817; (1 letter)** (Folder 12.345)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Sam F. Milbank, Co. to Vassar Co., 31 Mar 1818; (1 letter)** (Folder 12.346)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Clark Moore, Co. to Vassar Co., 31 Mar 1818; (1 letter)** (Folder 14.347)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Dodge, Daniel to Vassar Co., 6 Apr 1818; (1 letter)** (Folder 12.348)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Hewitt, Thomas to Vassar, 15 Apr 1818; (1 letter)** (Folder 12.349)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Stokes, [?]udway to Vassar Co., 21 Apr 1818; (1 letter)** (Folder 12.350)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Dodge, Daniel to Vassar Co., 4 May 1818; (1 letter)** (Folder 12.351)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Dodge, Daniel to Vassar Co., 4 May 1818; (1 letter)** (Folder 12.351)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Illingworth, Benjamin to Vassar, 27 May 1818; (1 letter)** (Folder 14.352)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Benjamin, J. to Vassar, Co., 3 Jun 1818; (1 letter)** (Folder 14.353)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Benjamin, J. to Vassar, Co., 5 Jun 1818; (1 letter)** (Folder 14.354)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Taylor, M.W. to Vassar, Co., 5 Jun 1818; (1 letter)** (Folder 14.355)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Dodge, D. to Vassar, Co., 27 Jun 1818; (1 letter)** (Folder 14.356)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Dodge, Daniel to Vassar, Co., 4 Aug 1818; (1 letter)** (Folder 12.357)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Dodge, Daniel to Vassar Co., 12 Aug 1818; (1 letter)** (Folder 12.358)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Stokes, [?]udway to Vassar, Co., 3 Oct 1818; (1 letter)** (Folder 12.359)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Benjamin, J. to Vassar, Co., 14 Oct 1818; (1 letter)** (Folder 14.360)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Dodge, D. to Vassar, Co., 16 Oct 1818; (1 letter)** (Folder 14.361)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Taylor, M.W. to Vassar, Co., 17 Oct 1818; (1 letter)** (Folder 14.362)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: [?]ker to Vassar, Co., 4 Nov 1818; (1 letter)** (Folder 14.363)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: [Fraser?], Alex to Vassar, Co., 5 Nov 1818; (1 letter)** (Folder 15.364)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Dodge, D. to Vassar, Co., 11 Nov 1818; (1 letter)** (Folder 15.365)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Dodge, D. to Vassar, Co., 21 Nov 1818; (1 letter)** (Folder 15.366)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Clark, Will F. to Vassar, Co., 25 Nov 1818; (1 letter)** (Folder 15.367)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Gifford, Isaac to M. Conklin, 10 Dec 1818; (1 letter)** (Folder 15.368)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Jackson, Brown to Vassar, Co., 12 Dec 1818; (1 letter)** (Folder 15.369)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Vassar to N.P. Tallmadge (original in New York Public Library), 15 Mar 1830; (1 letter) (Folder 15.370)
  - Matthew Vassar, Co., correspondence: Vassar to George P. Oakley (original in New York Public Library), 29 Mar 1830; (1 letter) (Folder 15.371)